<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
  <title>amuffin&#39;s blog</title>
  <subtitle>various microblogs, ramblings, fun thematic gatherings of links, and other blog posts.</subtitle>
  <link href="https://amuffin.is-a.dev/blog/feed.xml" rel="self" />
  <link href="https://amuffin.is-a.dev/" />
  <updated>2025-02-27T00:00:00Z</updated>
  <id>https://amuffin.is-a.dev/</id>
  <author>
    <name>amuffin</name>
  </author>
  <entry>
    <title>perceptual color spaces</title>
    <link href="https://amuffin.is-a.dev/blog/perceptually-uniform/" />
    <updated>2025-02-27T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <id>https://amuffin.is-a.dev/blog/perceptually-uniform/</id>
    <content type="html">
&lt;p&gt;
Have I really not made a post about perceptually uniform color spaces yet? They&#39;re pretty cool.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
check out these links!
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://bottosson.github.io/posts/colorwrong/&quot;&gt;https://bottosson.github.io/posts/colorwrong/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://bottosson.github.io/misc/colorpicker/&quot;&gt;https://bottosson.github.io/misc/colorpicker/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://cran.r-project.org/web/packages/viridis/vignettes/intro-to-viridis.html&quot;&gt;https://cran.r-project.org/web/packages/viridis/vignettes/intro-to-viridis.html&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hollow Knight soundtrack is pretty nice. &lt;/p&gt;</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>grr tedium</title>
    <link href="https://amuffin.is-a.dev/blog/tedium/" />
    <updated>2025-02-25T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <id>https://amuffin.is-a.dev/blog/tedium/</id>
    <content type="html">
&lt;p&gt;
This is a lot of work because this is such an old project that 
my repo is still named &quot;master&quot; instead of &quot;main,&quot; which is what I think is messing things up.
&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;p&gt;
Should be fixed now?
&lt;/p&gt;</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>wave function collapse and the duck konundrum</title>
    <link href="https://amuffin.is-a.dev/blog/waveFnDuck/" />
    <updated>2025-02-15T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <id>https://amuffin.is-a.dev/blog/waveFnDuck/</id>
    <content type="html">
&lt;p&gt;I found a wave function collapse explanation that was really cool: &lt;a href=&quot;https://robertheaton.com/2018/12/17/wavefunction-collapse-algorithm/&quot;&gt;
https://robertheaton.com/2018/12/17/wavefunction-collapse-algorithm/&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;reminds me of &lt;a href=&quot;https://puzzles.mit.edu/2000/set5/6/Puzzle.html&quot;&gt;The Duck Konundrum&lt;/a&gt;, somehow.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>eleventy and more updates</title>
    <link href="https://amuffin.is-a.dev/blog/eleventy/" />
    <updated>2025-02-13T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <id>https://amuffin.is-a.dev/blog/eleventy/</id>
    <content type="html">
&lt;p&gt;site generated with eleventy. now. ouch so much work. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;see: &lt;a href=&quot;https://brandur.org/fragments/dark-mode-notes&quot;&gt;https://brandur.org/fragments/dark-mode-notes&lt;/a&gt; where apparently I should apparently 
have had that darkmode.js inline. and so it is, now.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;go listen/watch Giant Steps the jazz thing&lt;/p&gt;</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>dithering and age of empires 2</title>
    <link href="https://amuffin.is-a.dev/blog/dithering/" />
    <updated>2025-02-13T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <id>https://amuffin.is-a.dev/blog/dithering/</id>
    <content type="html">
&lt;p&gt;oooo dithering ooooo! it makes things look really pretty. I think i have a laptop sticker somewhere that&#39;s dithered clouds or something and it 
looks real nice. Check out this tool for dithering: &lt;a href=&quot;https://doodad.dev/dither-me-this/&quot;&gt;https://doodad.dev/dither-me-this/&lt;/a&gt;.
Ordered dithering with mat height 2 or 4 looks great. the Commodore pallet is great. b and w is fine.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Also aoe2 is really funny for having a &lt;a href=&quot;https://ageofempires.fandom.com/wiki/Taunt&quot;&gt;soundboard&lt;/a&gt; with taunts that get played globally when you 
type in numbers. I&#39;ve been using number 7 &quot;aaaaaaa.&quot; pretty often. In a game once where I did something stupid with monks, the enemy team 
bm&#39;d me with &quot;What is your strategy?&quot; &quot;Attack the enemy with monks.&quot; Had me on the floor.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some honorable mentions are dadgum (sounds like &quot;Dad? Gone!&quot;) and the iconic wololo.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://idialedyournumber.bandcamp.com/album/hourglass&quot;&gt;idialedyournumber&lt;/a&gt; sounds really nice. Found them from Bunny Goes 2 Business School on youtube.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>league story</title>
    <link href="https://amuffin.is-a.dev/blog/LMFAOshaco/" />
    <updated>2024-06-02T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <id>https://amuffin.is-a.dev/blog/LMFAOshaco/</id>
    <content type="html">
&lt;p&gt;
  Just playing a game of league, shaco mirror matchup support. Ours was winning and we were hard winning as a team, but 
  the enemy shaco got so tilted in all chat that our fed master yi had such a good laugh they started a surrender vote and
  we voted 3 yes/2 no to surrender LMFAO 
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
  what a time to be alive
&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>techno cosplayer</title>
    <link href="https://amuffin.is-a.dev/blog/lost_techno/" />
    <updated>2024-05-28T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <id>https://amuffin.is-a.dev/blog/lost_techno/</id>
    <content type="html">
&lt;p&gt;I had to hard reset my phone so I lost all non-backed up photos but I just realized that means I also lost
    selfies I took with a cosplay Technoblade :(&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
    I miss Techno, he&#39;s probably the only person I would be fine with watching youtube for. I don&#39;t really
    care about any other content creator&#39;s content, they&#39;re all not really as captivating? Not sure how 
    to put it. Michael Reeves is pretty nice though, but that doesn&#39;t count because I&#39;m moving the goalposts.
    Techno made probably the only vlogs I&#39;ll ever be excited to watch. Sad I won&#39;t get to see new ones.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
    His visual persona is so cool as well, with so many fan fiction (text, image, animation, etc) made with it and others.
    Philza is cool too, crow god and all. Passerine is a good fanfiction. I printed out and hand bound it.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
    The cosplayer had the techno dangling earring too. Darn. I should keep more regular backups or smth.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://youtu.be/SvLKKGwk-EU?si=Sfi40ZCsDF8gL8eT&quot;&gt;pov: you are in middle school from 2009-2012 :3 (Part 1)&lt;/a&gt;lmfao&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>league nostalgia</title>
    <link href="https://amuffin.is-a.dev/blog/league/" />
    <updated>2024-05-28T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <id>https://amuffin.is-a.dev/blog/league/</id>
    <content type="html">
&lt;p&gt;
    played a couple of games of league, recently we&#39;ve gotten a few of the friend group into it and it&#39;s actually pretty
    nice sometimes, i have my ye olden days middle school nostalgia of also being guided through my first few, then 
    ten, then hundred, then many games. 
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
    wejust had such a silly and fun game being friendly with the enemies and our team, me on brand mid, the friend on nami 
    support, a random adc&#39;ing them that hard carried, a off meta yi top against our illaoi, a enemy bot duo that was an
    adc ez also coaching a supp lux on her third ever game in the moba genre. it really was memories of the good times.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;league soundtrack is good and their music videos, especially the worlds anthems, have so much lore put into them. (irl 
    comp league lore). 
    ignite is an old but good one. legends never die is a classic. RISE, too.
&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>typst, latex (with garamond!), and tectonic</title>
    <link href="https://amuffin.is-a.dev/blog/typesetting/" />
    <updated>2024-03-05T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <id>https://amuffin.is-a.dev/blog/typesetting/</id>
    <content type="html">
&lt;p&gt;
Typst and Latex are pretty cool. This is about to get pretty technical, because I&#39;m probably also going to use this to backup knowledge of how to repoduce my
typsetting setup.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
  I&#39;ve been typesetting a lot lately for school and for fun. Latex is nice because it&#39;s been around for so long, so it&#39;s math typesetting, typesetting in general 
  abilities are really guaranteed everywhere. If something doesn&#39;t work, you can hack it to work.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
  The Tectonic typesetting project is also really cool. It made getting a latex compiler on a new machine so fast, no need to download a whole TexLive 5gb 
  package or whatever. I guess things like TinyTex exist but ehhh, I learned LaTex on texlive so I&#39;m a bit averse to learning a different style of package
  management now. (TexLive&#39;s package management being: no need to, you&#39;ve already installed the entire damn thing :p.) To get tectonic to play nice with Latex Workshop
  for VS Code, all you need is 
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;
// for using vscode/latex workshop/tectonic together 
// this is the v1 code version https://github.com/tectonic-typesetting/tectonic/discussions/896#discussioncomment-2850685
&quot;latex-workshop.latex.recipe.default&quot;: &quot;tectonic&quot;,
&quot;latex-workshop.latex.recipes&quot;: [
  {
    &quot;name&quot;: &quot;tectonic&quot;,
    &quot;tools&quot;: [&quot;tectonic&quot;]
  }
],
&quot;latex-workshop.latex.tools&quot;: [
  {
    &quot;name&quot;: &quot;tectonic&quot;,
    &quot;command&quot;: &quot;tectonic&quot;,
    &quot;args&quot;: [&quot;%DOC%.tex&quot;, &quot;--keep-intermediates&quot;],
    &quot;env&quot;: {}
  }
],
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
  in a settings.json. If tectonic ever finishes upgrading to v2, there&#39;s an updated solution in that same github link. But like this, I can preserve
  pdflatex/tectonic compile outputs. (ie, not need to have the default directory tree for tectonic v2).
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
  Though, I had to learn package managing anyways, in a way. I&#39;ve kinda fallen in love with EB Garamond, and you can apparently get that font through LaTex.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;
~$ wget https://tug.org/fonts/getnonfreefonts/install-getnonfreefonts
~$ texlua install-getnonfreefonts
~$ getnonfreefonts garamond
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
I had some weird errors about texlua not having permissions to edit the /etc/... dir, and sudo texlua not being able to find texlua at all, but
sudo su was a quick workaround that let everything run correctly.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
  After that, any .tex document with
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;
&#92;usepackage[T1]{fontenc}
&#92;usepackage[urw-garamond]{mathdesign}
&#92;let&#92;circledS&#92;undefined
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
  included is able to render the document in garamond. Undefining circledS has to be done because it urw-garamond sets it, which conflicts with 
  amssymb. Amssym&#39;s looks much better. Unfortunately, it seems like tectonic won&#39;t be able to support this any time soon as per 
  &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/tectonic-typesetting/tectonic/issues/478&quot;&gt;https://github.com/tectonic-typesetting/tectonic/issues/478&lt;/a&gt;.
  &quot;OK, I&#39;ve identified what&#39;s going on here. The TeXLive 2020 update won&#39;t help, unfortunately. In the standard TeXLive stack, the PDF generation process automatically generates a &quot;PK&quot; font file from the requested BBM font, by launching an external program mktexpk. Tectonic isn&#39;t in a position to do that, leading to the missing-font problem.&quot;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
  I don&#39;t quite like how the numbers are rendered, though. The 0 character especially looks quite off, very wide. Not like EB Garamond that comes with
  google docs. Garamond-Math created at &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/YuanshengZhao/Garamond-Math/&quot;&gt;https://github.com/YuanshengZhao/Garamond-Math/&lt;/a&gt; and
  &lt;a href=&quot;https://mirrors.mit.edu/CTAN/fonts/garamond-math/Garamond-Math.pdf&quot;&gt;https://mirrors.mit.edu/CTAN/fonts/garamond-math/Garamond-Math.pdf&lt;/a&gt; is absolutely
  beautiful, though. Check out those sample fonts! Mwah.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
  Note to self: i should probably make a blog post doubling as an archive for my dotfile/home folder structure and all.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
Been on a Bastille kick. Laughter Lines and Icarus are good songs.
&lt;/p&gt;</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>latex</title>
    <link href="https://amuffin.is-a.dev/blog/latexrant/" />
    <updated>2024-01-07T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <id>https://amuffin.is-a.dev/blog/latexrant/</id>
    <content type="html">
&lt;p&gt;I use latex a looot now because of university. Tangent: it feels so weird to be the person now, saying &quot;because
of university.&quot; It&#39;s not too long ago that I was the young high schooler looking at those OLD PEOPLE at afar. anyways,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Latex is cool i guess. I managed to get anki (the flash carding program, not the weird cable television-advertised 
hotwheels ripoff(?)) working with latex which is pretty cool, I can study all my fancy formulas with anki and 
spaced repetition now. Though, for some reason the font rendering is so ugly compared to normal latex i think.
Not sure if this is a dvipng (program used to render the images for latex to anki, i think) issue or just me
getting placebo effected from the font just being larger.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Early into the semester, I wrote this gem with latex: &lt;a href=&quot;https://amuffin.is-a.dev/blog/latexrant/lady_tigers_unsolved.pdf&quot;&gt;./lady_tigers_unsolved.pdf&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I forgot to mention that the end goal was to find where the lady was. Whoops, mb&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A friend recommended The Predatory Wasp of the Palisades Is Out to Get Us! by Sufjan Stevens. It&#39;s really good.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
</feed>